(デイダラ)オイラの究極芸術だ。
This is my ultimate art...!
これから オイラは自爆する。
Now I will detonate myself.
《サスケ : コイツ…》
He's...!
死んで オイラは芸術になる。
With death, I will become art.
今までにない爆発は この地に
今までにない傷跡を残し➡
This never-before-seen explosion
will leave
a never-before-seen scar
on this land.
そして オイラの芸術は
今までにない称賛を受けるだろう。
And...! My art will win
never-before-seen admiration!
《トビ… 悪いな》
Sorry, Tobi...
Hmm?
オイラの称賛のなか
テメエは確実に死ぬ！
In the midst of my admiration,
you will definitely die!!
半径10キロが爆発範囲だ。
An explosion that will cover
a ten-kilometer radius...
逃げきれやしねえぜ うん！
You won't be able to get away!
さぁ 怯えろ…
驚嘆しろ！ 絶望しろ!!
Now, tremble with fear!
Be in awe! Despair!!
Scream!
泣きわめけ！ オイラの芸術は…。
My art is...
(デイダラ)喝！ 爆発だ!!
An explosion!!
(トビ)なっ！
Wha--?!
何だ あれは!?
What is that?!
(キバ)何だ!?
What the--?!
(パックン)カカシ あれは？
Kakashi, what is that?
(カカシ)この感じ…
あのチャクラは 暁の…。
This chakra...
It's that Akatsuki member...
(ヒナタ)な 何だろう…。
Wh-What could it be?
(ナルト)行ってみるってばよ。
(ヤマト)あぁ。
Let's go check it out!
Right!
Look!
《香燐 : サスケ… まさか…》
Sasuke... It can't be...!
《サスケのチャクラが感じられない！》
I can't sense Sasuke's chakra!
(水月)あの辺りは集合場所だ。
That's near our rendezvous point...
まさか!?
Don't tell me he's...!
Damn! It's just as I feared!
って！ その まさかじゃないか!!
(ゼツ)デイダラのヤツ 自爆したな。
That Deidara...
He blew himself up.
トビは どこかな？
Where's Tobi?
(ゼツ)巻き添えだな
あの爆発の中にいただろうから。
Probably dead...
He was within the blast range...
Disappearance
Deidara is dead.
(ゼツ)デイダラが死んだ。
In the end, he went out with a bang.
最後は己で大爆発だ。
(鬼鮫)あらら
またメンバーが減っちゃいましたね。
Oh dear.
Another member has been lost...
彼は 結構 強かったと思いますが。
And I thought he was
pretty strong.
で どっちにやられたんです？
So? Which one did him in?
サスケか 九尾の人柱力か？
Sasuke? Or the Nine-Tails' Jinchuriki?
サスケだ。 ただしね…➡
It was Sasuke.
However...
サスケも死んだみたいだよ。
It looks like Sasuke is dead too.
道連れですか…。
Deidara took Sasuke down
with him, huh...?
(ペイン)感謝するんだな イタチ。
デイダラが厄介払いをしてくれたんだ。
You should feel grateful, Itachi.
Deidara did you a favor
and got rid of your problem.
ん～ あと何か忘れてるような…。
Hmm... I feel like
we've forgotten something...
トビも死んだみたいだよ。 デイダラのヤツ
見境なく爆発しやがった。
Looks like Tobi is dead too.
That Deidara detonated himself
without regard for his surroundings.
そうそう トビでしたか…。 しかし
あの逃げ腰が逃げ遅れるとは➡
Ah yes, Tobi.
It must've been quite a jutsu
if that chicken was unable to escape.
相当 たいした術だったんですね。
まぁいい。 あの程度の男なら
いくらでも補充は利く。
No matter...
He can easily be replaced.
デイダラは惜しかったが…。
The loss of Deidara, however,
is unfortunate.
私は彼が好きでしたよ。
I liked Tobi.
陰鬱な この組織の場を
和ませる能力なら➡
When it came to lightening the mood
in our rather gloomy organization,
トビも たいした能力者でしたがね。
Tobi was quite talented.
オレは行く。
せめて静かにデイダラを弔うとしよう。
I'm going.
I shall mourn Deidara's death in silence.
だったら ボクはトビの弔いを…。
暇だな…。
Then I'll mourn for Tobi.
You must really be bored, huh?
(水月)蛇の紋章が消えたら と…
When the crest of
the snake vanishes...
Then...I do this...
コイツをこうやって…。
サスケの血をちょいと垂らして…。
Add a drop of Sasuke's blood...
よし。
All right.
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
コ… コイツが大蛇丸の口寄せ マンダか。
S-So, this is Orochimaru's
Summoning Jutsu...
Manda...
大蛇丸でさえ手を焼いていたコイツを
どうやって…。
Even Orochimaru had trouble
controlling this guy.
How did Sasuke manage to...?
ん？
《なるほど… 幻術か》
I see. He used genjutsu...
Whoa, you're a mess!
なんだ ボロボロじゃないか！
誰とやり合ったんだ？
Who did you fight?
You...had the nerve...
(マンダ)この… オレ様を…➡
利用しやがって… このクソガキ…。
to use me...
You damned brat...
その目…
その目で オレ様を操ったのか…。
Those eyes...you controlled me...
with those eyes...
I...of all...people...
このオレ様を…。
あ～ぁ 死んじゃったよ。
Oh-ohh, he's dead.
マンダって あの大蛇丸の
いちばんのペットでしょ？
Wasn't Manda Orochimaru's
favorite pet?
動物は もっと大切にしなきゃ。
それに ムリやり幻術かけてさぁ。
You ought to treat animals better...
And the whole manipulation
with the genjutsu...
There wasn't time to think.
I had no choice...
ギリギリだったからな…。
そんな余裕はなかった。
(香燐)いた！
Found you!
やっぱりここか！
I figured you'd be here!
Your chakra suddenly disappeared,
so I wondered what had happened...
急に チャクラが消えたから
どうしたのかと思えば➡
Did you transport yourself?!
飛んでたのか！
マンダの中に入って➡
You hid yourself inside Manda,
then used the Transportation Technique
to escape into another dimension...
時空間忍術で別空間へ
飛んで逃げた… のはいいけど➡
なんでそんなにボロボロなの？
So why are you in such bad shape?
飛ぶ寸前に
マンダと一緒に爆風を受けた。
Just before escaping,
we both got hit by the blast wave.
相手は暁だ。
思った以上のやり手でな…。
My opponent was one of the Akatsuki.
He was stronger than I expected...
《傷だらけのサスケも かっこいい》
Sasuke all cut up and bruised
is also hot...
とにかく少し休養をとらないとね。
In any case, he needs time to rest.
Right, Karin?
なぁ 香燐？
Ahem! How pathetic!
だらしねえ！
それでも大蛇丸をやった男かよ!!
And you call yourself the man
who killed Orochimaru?!
大蛇丸は もともと弱っていた。
それだけの話だ。
Orochimaru was already weakened
to begin with.
That's all there is to it.
(鬼鮫)まだ やみませんねぇ。
この時期に この地域で➡
It just won't stop.
It's strange to have this much rain
around here at this time of year.
こうも降るのは
おかしいんですが。
お体に障りますよ。
You'll ruin your health.
冷酷なあなたが
今 何を考えているのか➡
I don't know what someone as cold as you
could be thinking about right now...
それは わかりませんが➡
ここからだと
泣いてるように見えますよ。
But from here,
you look as though you are crying.
弟さんのことなら 残念でしたね。
It's too bad about your younger brother...
これで うちは一族は
あなた一人になってしまった。
You are now the sole survivor
of the Uchiha clan.
(イタチ)いや…。
ん？
No.
Hmm?
アイツは死んでない。 それに…。
He's not dead. Also...
どういうことです？
What do you mean?
(イタチ)雨が… やんだな。
The rain...has stopped.
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto!
Looks like it caught all our attention.
みんな気になって
駆けつけたようだね。
何があったんだ!?
What happened?!
There are signs that Sasuke
was just here.
サスケ君が さっきまで
ここにいた形跡があるの。
アイツのニオイが
かすかだが漂っている。
It's very faint,
but his scent still lingers.
I also detect other scents.
それに いくつか
他のニオイも残ってる。
どういうことだ？
What does it mean?
(シノ)この地形の傷跡からして➡
From the damage to the terrain,
I'd say there was a battle here.
ここで 戦闘があったと
考えられる。
やっぱりだ。
この 他のニオイのひとつは➡
I knew it! One of the other scents
belongs to that fellow in town
町で嗅いだ
サスケのニオイと混じってたヤツだ。
on whom I detected Sasuke's scent.
Huh?
どうやら サスケの近くについて➡
Looks like there are others
traveling alongside Sasuke.
一緒に行動しているヤツらが
いるようだ。 同伴者がいる。
He has a companion.
じゃあ あのとき…。
Then, back there...
おそらく サスケは
小隊を組んで移動してたな。
It's probable that...
Sasuke has formed his unit.
他の５つのニオイのうち ひとつは➡
One of the five other scents belongs
to Deidara from Akatsuki.
暁のデイダラと呼ばれていた男。
え… アイツは自爆して➡
Wasn't he the one
who self-destructed
カカシ先生の術で
異空間に飛ばされたんじゃ…。
and was transported to another dimension
by your jutsu, Sensei?!
どうやら 自爆に見せかけて➡
It seems he faked
his own death to escape...
逃げていた
ということのようだな。
で ヤツら暁は➡
The Akatsuki operate in two-man cells,
so there are three left.
ツーマンセルで行動するから
残りは３つ。
サスケは フォーマンセルで行動している。
Sasuke is moving with
a four-man cell.
Who cares how many there are.
何人だろうと関係ねえ！
Let's get moving and
trace Sasuke's scent!
さっさと サスケのニオイを
追うってばよ！
それが ダメなんだ。
We can't.
は？ なんで!?
Huh? Why not?
ニオイが ここで なくなってる。
The scent stops here.
どういうことだ!?
What does that mean?!
こういう場合は サスケが爆発で
跡形もなく消し飛んだか➡
Usually in a situation like this,
either Sasuke was blasted to bits
by the explosion...
あるいは 時空間忍術で
飛んだと考えるのが普通だ。
or Sasuke used
the Transportation Technique to escape.
時空間忍術？
Transportation Technique...?
(キバ)どうやら 後者のようだな。
It's probably the latter.
今のオレは 犬以上に鼻が利く。
見つけたぜ サスケ！
My sense of smell is keener
than a dog's right now.
I've found Sasuke!
《忍犬以上の鼻とは
成長したな キバ。
A nose that's sharper than
the ninja hounds...?
Impressive, Kiba.
さすがは 犬塚家だ》
Just what I would expect
from a member of the Inuzuka clan.
キバ 案内してくれ。
Kiba, lead the way!
(小南)ペイン 来て。 彼が来たわ。
Come, Pain...
He's here.
And...what of Sasuke?
で サスケのほうは？
いい感じだ。
He's coming along nicely...
写輪眼の力を
十二分に発揮していた。
He was using the Sharingan's power
to his fullest...
His eyes will surpass Itachi's...
あれは イタチ以上の眼になる。
機は熟した。
ヤツも覚悟は決まっているだろう。
The time has come.
He must be ready as well.
そう長くはないからな。
After all, he doesn't have much time.
じゃあ 九尾のほうは？
Then what about the Nine-Tails?
お前が狩れ。
You hunt it.
As leader, failure is not an option.
リーダーとして失敗は許さん。
INN OKOSHI
ヘッ
イタチをやるって言ってたくせに➡
Hah! You talked about killing Itachi...
こんなザマじゃ
しばらくは動けねえぞ。
You won't be able to move around
for some time in that condition!
ここんところ 歩きづめだったから
ちょうどいい。 休暇がとれる。
We've been moving nonstop lately.
It's a good chance to rest up.
テメエは休みっぱなしだったじゃ
ねえか。 この貧弱野郎！
All you've done is rest,
you feeble punk!
There, finished.
よし 終わりだ。
(水月)北アジトで➡
You didn't do a thing at
the northern hideout,
なんにもしなかったキミには
言われたくないね。
so don't start telling me
what to do now.
なんだと コラ！ テメエやんのか オゥ。
ああ やってやろうじゃねえか！
What?! Wanna make something of it?!
Then let's do it!
Enough already!
いいかげんにしろ。
Suigetsu, Karin...
Have you gathered data on Itachi?
水月 香燐。 それより
イタチの情報は集まったのか？
ボロボロのテメエが
偉そうに言ってんじゃねえよ。
You're in no shape to act so bossy!
暁ってヤツらの情報は
いくつかつかんだが➡
I've picked up some tips
about Akatsuki,
イタチについての
はっきりしたものはなかったよ。
but nothing specific
about Itachi himself.
ウチは ゼロ。
I got zero.
ただ ヤツらは ある特定の人物➡
Seems they're targeting
specific people though...
特別なチャクラを持つ者たちを
狙っているようだ。
People with special chakra.
特別なチャクラ。
Special chakra...?
(重吾)オレは動物に語りかけ
暁のアジトをいくつか把握した。
I did some talking to animals and
located a number of Akatsuki hideouts.
It seems they always sense
その周辺では いつも大きく
イヤなチャクラを感じるらしい。
a powerful, unpleasant chakra
around each area.
動物たちは そう言ってる。
That's what the animals have told me.
へぇ 低能な動物たちも
チャクラを感じ取ることができるのか。
Wow, even simpleminded animals
can sense chakra, eh...?
いや 低能だからこそか。
まるで香燐みたいだね。
Or maybe it's because
they're simpleminded...
Just like you Karin!
What did you say, you jerk?!
っだと テメエ！
Suigetsu! This time,
you're not getting away with it!
水月 テメエ 今度という今度は
絶対許さねえ！
(水月)おい ちょっ… 待て。 おい。
Hey... W-Wait...hey!
殺す。 殺したい。
Kill... I want to kill...
- Huh?
- Huh?!
うぉ～っ！
INN OKOSHI
うぉ～。
やばい。 重吾の殺人衝動が。
Shoot! Jugo's killing impulse is loose!
Sasuke! Hurry it--!
サスケ 早くしろ。
落ち着け 重吾。
Calm down, Jugo.
ハァ ハァ。
す すまない。
S-Sorry...
It's your fault, Karin.
Screaming and making such a fuss.
香燐が悪いんだぞ
ギャーギャーと騒いで。
あぁ？ お前だって。
What? You too...
香燐 キミは そうやって
ボクを挑発して➡
You constantly try to provoke me, Karin.
何を企んでるんだい？
What are you up to?
前にも言ったと思うけど➡
I've already told you.
自分の目的のためにも
サスケから離れるつもりはないよ。
I don't intend to leave Sasuke
for my own reasons.
I-I'm not up to anything.
べ 別に ウチは
なにも企んでるわけじゃなくて➡
I'm just trying to test your...
純粋に 水月 お前の気持を…。
オレには… オレには サスケが必要だ。
I...I need Sasuke.
君麻呂の代わりになるのは…
サスケだけなんだ。
The only one who can
replace Kimimaro...is Sasuke.
サスケは オレの檻になると
言ってくれた。
Sasuke said he would
become my cage...
さっきのように オレの衝動を
止められるのは➡
Right now, only Sasuke can
stop my urges,
今は サスケしかいない。
like he did earlier...
でもね コイツはどうあれ➡
Still... I don't know about her,
but our cages are unlocked.
その檻ってヤツには
鍵なんてかかってないんだよ。
いつでも 誰でも抜け出せる。
なのにな…。
We can escape anytime we wish.
And yet...
間違いない こっちだ。
I'm sure of it. It's this way!
From his scent,
I can tell he's stopped moving.
ヤツのニオイは 動きを止めている。
It seems he's resting.
どうやら 潜伏しているようだぜ。
チャンスだな。
It's our chance.
《サスケ… お前への道が
つながったってばよ》
Sasuke...
Our paths have finally crossed.
うずまきナルト… あれは
ただのガキではなくなった。
Naruto Uzumaki...
He's no longer just a kid.
いまや たいそうな術を身につけ
仲間も多い。
He has now mastered
a formidable jutsu...
and has many comrades.
簡単には いかんぞ。
It won't be easy.
一撃で あの角都の命を
二つ削った。
ターゲットをおそるべしとする
言葉は ちりに等しい。
ペインは 負けたことがないのだから。
フフッ… まっ それもそうだ。
話は終わりだ。
他のメンバーに
残りの人柱力を急がせろ。
わかっている。
いよいよだ… 我らが
目的を達成するのも あとわずか。
そうなれば すべてが
本来の形に戻るのだ。
写輪眼の本当の力が…
この うちはマダラの力が！
また 空が鳴き出した。
ペイン あなた…。
(カプリコ)開け ベルパラソの狩人 サマグィ。
レイラの娘を仕留めてこい。